<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<phq9>
    <questions>
        <question id="1">
            How often have you been bothered that you have little interest or pleasure in doing things over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="2">
            How often have you been bothered by feeling down, depressed, irritable, or hopeless over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="3">
            How often have you been bothered by trouble falling asleep, staying asleep, or sleeping too much over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="4">
            How often have you been bothered by feeling tired, or having little energy over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="5">
            How often have you been bothered that you have poor appetite, weight loss, or overeating over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="6">
            How often have you been bothered by feeling bad about yourself – or feeling that you are a failure, or that you have let yourself or your family down over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="7">
            How often have you been bothered that you have trouble concentrating on things like school work, reading, or watching TV over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="8">
            How often have you been bothered by moving or speaking so slowly that other people could have noticed? Or the opposite – being so fidgety or restless that you were moving around a lot more than usual over the last two weeks?
        </question>
        <question id="9">
            How often have you been bothered by thoughts that you would be better off dead, or of hurting yourself in some way over the last two weeks?
        </question>
    </questions>

    <effect>
        <question id="1">
            If you clicked on any problems above, how difficult have they made it for you to do your work?
        </question>
        <question id="2">
            If you clicked on any problems above, how difficult have they made it for you to take care of things at home?
        </question>
        <question id="3">
            If you clicked on any problems above, how difficult have they made it for you to get along with other people?
        </question>
    </effect>

    <mc1>
        <answer score="0">
            Not at all
        </answer>
        <answer score="1">
            Several days
        </answer>
        <answer score="2">
            More than half the days
        </answer>
        <answer score="3">
            Nearly every day
        </answer>
    </mc1>

    <mc2>
        <answer score="0">
            Not difficult at all
        </answer>
        <answer score="1">
            Somewhat difficult
        </answer>
        <answer score="2">
            Very difficult
        </answer>
        <answer score="3">
            Extremely difficult
        </answer>
    </mc2>
</phq9>